all right I want to summarize a few
things that I was reminded of with
regard to postest I'm actually currently
working on a thing called Kates app-
postgress SQL DB backup it will be just
a Coran job it's one of the smallest
simplest uh kuet applications that you
could create um but I hit a number of
blockers uh along the way and mistakes
that I want to tell you about that
relate to me thinking about all of this
stuff like somebody from 2001 when I
first learned postest and put everything
out there um the the I got the part
where you make a postgress
server uh in a Docker container correct
and for that I actually wrote a
script um just in a tools directory here
called start start postrest
container uh you know chat GPT did
remind me how to use podman I deci use
podman versus Docker and um that you
know I'm exposed for 5432 which allows
it to be seen on a local
machine um or anything you know any
other container that can talk to that Lo
machine you need to expose those ports
out and remember I put the environment
variables in the EnV file which are
super
secret uh this is a really common
container thing that I don't necessarily
like but I do it anyway postest user my
my um uh my password I got to shut that
up I don't know if I'm going to be able
to shut that up which which one was it
SC oh I'll do that next time so anyway I
put these these passwords in there um so
they would be set up during the
initialization of the database and then
and then I ran the the thing that
started the container okay so there's no
kubernetes involved yet uh this is just
containers so I can write the test
script around the PG dump and and and
put some sample data in there and
practice doing the dump of the data um
you could just run you know the PG Dum
command and do the do a on line and put
in bash script but you know right now
I'm trying to kind of flush it
out um a volume mounted a local data
directory um so that this other system
can see it and when I'm running uh
commands that will load data from that
directory I can start do that I haven't
done any of that yet and then uh where
the imag is and I'm pulling it down from
doer Hub which I hate but because it
doesn't exist anywhere else um so so
that that got me the database running
but then the problem started um How do
you access your database right and these
are extremely newbie problems that I had
because I've been writing go code and
doing all kinds of other things at work
I haven't been doing any of this I
haven't touched postgress in years so
the first thing I did wrong was I even
though I'm running in a VM I like oh I
need psql so I'll just Pudo app to
install you know postgress right no
wrong because because why number one I
had to add an apt repository to get the
latest version of postgress uh to get
the psql and I want to get PG dump so I
can do the dump and you can still see
the error here on top of my screen PG
dump version 14 doesn't match version 16
so that's one of many errors that could
be avoided by setting up a test
container client client container to
access the other container you can
probably combine them but I think
containing it that's the solution if you
wanted to jump ahead that's the answer
and I'm going to start doing that
tomorrow and I'll I'll do a I'll do a
status update video on that so the what
what I'm getting at is that when in the
old days which you know I'm old um you
know you would set up a server and you
put a version on there and you of course
you're going to use package management
because it's easier but redhead and post
andun we are both you know notoriously
bad at keeping really you know back back
back level versions now I could fix this
I actually need to back up in test 16.4
that's the one we're using in in in in
our Harbor registry so that's the one
that I want to do that's the one I want
to back up but I can't do it if I'm
using the app package managers or I'm
using the OS package managers and why
would you right um You need to be able
to get the one that matches the one you
want which means you're going to need to
install post course in a different way
so by doing this uh I did a whole bunch
of thing and and not to mention the fact
that I had a leftover PG um
database uh PG database environment
variable in my bash RC from when I was
doing a co-working database for a long
time ago because it is nice to have you
know the most the localized version of
it so you can use the psq well command
and then all that other stuff gets
populated for you so you can just do
that right so I finally got the psql
command to work I got the PG dump that
work and everything uh so that you know
I can just do psql like this and I get a
database uh that's by you know setting
up that PG pass and then setting
environment variables correctly and all
that stuff that we would do in 2000 um
but but the problem is as soon as I got
that done and I started doing the thing
I wanted to do uh which was just PG dump
um you know I was like which version is
this even and it's like oh no you can't
use it so
um you can barely see it's the same era
that before the point of it is
that had I done had I created a client
container from the beginning which I was
going to do but I thought oh that's
going to be too much hassle if I created
a client container uh and a darker pile
for that or something and and just pull
down like I don't know like a a deban
container or even God it doesn't even
have to be that it could be anything
anything that can support uh the
installation of postc I could even
probably um do well now that I thinking
about it I could probably do all of this
on the actual container itself that's
probably what I'm going to try I've been
trying to decide whether I need two
containers to write this or not this is
all just during the test phase of it
before we even turn it into a uh because
we have to be able to test you know the
backing up the database which is super
easy it's just one command but we still
want to test I still want to test it
right and I want to tested in a Cron job
and put it in mini Cube and do all those
things and for that we have to have an
image um that contains um this stuff um
and you know I'm starting to think now
that I can probably just pull in the
postgress uh the post uh container image
as into the kubernetes uh pod in order
to do this Cron job um but I'm getting
ahead of myself so what I wanted to say
is if if you are inclined and most of
you probably are because you're younger
than me but if you're if you're inclined
to try to get your virtual machine uh so
that it has the same client and
everything that it needs to talk to your
database which is using the latest
container image good good chance it's
not going to match and it should have
been really obvious to me and it wasn't
so I'm just putting it out there so that
you can you can know that uh when you're
going to get it when you're going to try
this uh my current strategy going
forward is going to be to just use the
postrest image just use the postc crust
image as this I'll to see if it has
everything in it it's obviously got PG
dump and everything in there so all I
need to do at that point is Mount of
volume and have some data put the data
in there dump it then compare the two
sets of data um and in order for me to
use the the the psql command I will have
to exec into it I'll have to go into the
into the data I have to exec from the
command line um or I have to go into the
the container and do stuff and one of
the reasons I don't like that is because
I lose all of my fancy command line
stuff because I'm me just you know
really Bare Bones Debian system or
something and there are ways around that
uh I've made a workspace container in
the past um to get around that but it's
really big and Bloated it gets bigger as
you go because you want put all these
things in there so it's like so there is
something of a middle ground there that
I'm going to try to shoot for and that
is running just running oneliner Docker
commands against the running container
um but that's not how containers work
right they spin up a container in order
to run uh in order to execute a thing
and then they go away so uh if this is
the one that's containing the database
uh I kind of want it to be around with
and keep the data in it when I'm doing
the thing so um number of things I still
have to look into there and learn about
so uh that's all